MEGANCUMMINGS

ASPIRING SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

- 904.537.1699
- megcummingsl@gmail.com
- San Francisco, CA
- My GitHub
- www.meganelecta.com

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly
San Francisco, CA | 2019

B.A. Psychology

Columbia University New York, NY | 2009

SKILLS

- Salesforce
- Confluence/JIRA
- CRM (Netsuite)
- Anaplan
- Trello | Asana
- MS Office Suite
- Tableau

PROFILE

Software Engineer looking to build development experience expanding on over 9 years in deeply technical spaces, supporting high-stakes, fast-paced teams across Operations, Project Management, Product Launch and Sales. Proven ability to bring insightful solutions to complex problems across a variety of situations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS: JavaScript, React, APIs, jQuery, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

SERVER-SIDE & DATABASES: Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, JavaScript, SQL, Express

MANAGEMENT & DEPLOYMENT: Git, GitHub, Command Line, Heroku

METHODOLOGIES: Object-Oriented Programming | Test-Driven Development | Responsive Design | Authentication | User Stories | Wireframing | Agile Development/Scrum

CONCEPT PROJECTS

Beautify GitHub | Makeup Ecommerce Site (July 2019)

- Technologies Used: Django, PostgreSQL, CSS, Bootstrap, Python, Jinga, Psycop2, Sqlparse, Stripe, HTML, JavaScript
- Built entire backend web application, managing to solve for 'Add to Cart' & Checkout functionality, as well as Stripe Integration

Wayfarer GitHub | React SPA for Travel (August 2019)

- Technologies Used: React, BCrypt, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Axios, CSS, HTML, JavaScript
- Managed execution of the Backend, building complex Model structures, full CRUD functionality, authentication & authorization

MEGANCUMMINGS

CONCEPT PROJECTS (CONTINUED)

Shef GitHub | Personal Recipe Application (June 2019)

- Technologies Used: Node.js, Express, JQuery, JavaScript, EJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Mongo
- Developed, designed & debugged the web-application while pair-programming

EXPERIENCE

INDEPENDENT CONSULTANT

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2018 - PRESENT

Supporting a variety of companies across software and CPG industries, managing infrastructure, operations and analytical foundations of business.

- Worked collaboratively with Founding teams of early stage startups to develop robust business models and forecasting systems (Excel Macros) for use in investor pitch decks.
- Overhauled End-to-End Customer Journey for mid-level startup, optimizing processes for customer NPS score and customer satisfaction.

GOOGLE

SENIOR SALES OPERATIONS LEAD | PALO ALTO, CA | 2015 - 2018 SALES OPERATIONS LEAD | PALO ALTO, CA | 2014 - 2015

As Nest's Sales Operations Leader for North American Retail, I managed Operational support for Nest's largest business organization, integrating Nest's complex systems with Google's architecture.

- Successfully scaled all internal & external systems and processes to support product expansion across 5 new product families and internal sales growth of +120% annually.
- Served as Go-To-Market Program Manager as a 20% Project, gaining deep expertise across Product & Eng teams while bringing Nest's Thermostat E Launch to Market with the highest Launch Rating in Nest History.
- Led new Software Implementation efforts for new software (Salesforce & Anaplan), collaborating with software teams externally and internally for a seamless integration.

NEST LABS, INC

SALES OPERATIONS LEAD | PALO ALTO, CA | 2012 - 2014

- Joined at its early startup days, scaling systems and processes through rapid growth & Google acquisition.
- Supported Nest Partner growth over 2 years, building and maintaining forecasting systems, pricing systems and partner onboarding systems & processes.